Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Kathryn and we're talking today about health and getting sick.
我是Kathryn，今天我们聊的是健康和生病的话题。
That's right.
没错。
We are going to visit the doctor so we're feeling a little bit ill and well, we're going
我们要去看医生，所以我们感觉有点不舒服，而且我们要
to describe some of the symptoms that we have and the doctor is going to recommend some
描述一些症状，医生会推荐一些
medicine.
药。
All right.
好的。
So let's take a listen to today's dialogue and we'll be back in a moment to talk about
那么让我们听听今天的对话，稍后我们会回来讨论
what's going on.
发生了什么。
Good afternoon, Chloe.
下午好，Chloe。
I'm Dr. Evans.
我是Evans医生。
What seems to be the problem?
有什么问题吗？
Hi, Dr. Evans.
你好，Evans医生。
Thanks for seeing me on such short notice.
谢谢你这么快就接诊我。
When I woke up this morning, I had a really sore throat and a really bad cough.
今天早上醒来时，我喉咙很痛，咳嗽也很厉害。
I think I'm coming down with the flu.
我想我可能得了流感。
I see.
我明白了。
Yes, you do sound rather croaky.
是的，你听起来确实声音沙哑。
Well, let's have a look, shall we?
好吧，让我们检查一下，好吗？
Would you please open your mouth and say, ah?
请你张开嘴，说“啊”好吗？
Ah.
啊。
Good.
好的。
Yes.
是的。
Your tonsils are a little swollen and red.
你的扁桃体有点红肿。
How are your ears?
你的耳朵怎么样？
Blocked at all?
有堵塞吗？
A little, actually.
实际上有点。
My sinuses are a little blocked up as well.
我的鼻窦也有点堵塞。
I really feel terrible.
我真的感觉很难受。
Okay, Chloe.
好的，Chloe。
Can you please breathe in and out slowly for me while I listen to your chest?
请你慢慢地吸气和呼气，我听听你的胸部。
Wow, you really are all bunged up.
哇，你确实堵得很厉害。
You don't sound too good at all.
你听起来状态不太好。
Okay.
好的。
I'm going to set you up with a bunch of antibiotics.
我会给你开一些抗生素。
You will need to take these orange pills twice a day and these blue pills every evening.
这些橙色药片每天吃两次，这些蓝色药片每天晚上吃。
You will also have to take this cough medicine three times a day after meals.
你还需要每天饭后三次服用这种止咳药。
Finally, I am giving you an inhaler to use every time you feel breathless, just to clear
最后，我给你一个吸入器，每次感觉气短时使用，用来
up your lungs.
清理肺部。
Whoa, so many drugs.
哇，这么多药。
I hate swallowing pills.
我讨厌吞药片。
Am I able to go to work?
我能去上班吗？
Absolutely not.
绝对不行。
You are highly contagious.
你具有很强的传染性。
You don't want to infect the rest of your co-workers, do you?
你不想传染给其他同事吧？
I recommend staying in bed for at least three days and drinking plenty of fluids so you
我建议你至少卧床休息三天，多喝液体，这样
don't get weak and dehydrated.
就不会虚弱和脱水。
You can catch up on all the latest TV shows and movies.
你可以补看所有最新的电视节目和电影。
Okay.
好的。
Would you mind writing me a doctor's note for work?
你能给我开一张病假条吗？
Otherwise, they may think I'm faking it.
否则，他们可能以为我在装病。
Sure, no problem.
当然，没问题。
Here you are.
给你。
Now, off home and away to bed.
现在，回家上床休息吧。
If you have any questions, just give me a call.
如果你有任何问题，给我打电话。
Feel better soon and take care.
祝你早日康复，保重。
Thanks, Doc.
谢谢，医生。
Bye.
再见。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now let's take a look at six key words that we have prepared for you today on Language
现在让我们看看今天在“语言要点”中为大家准备的六个关键词。
Takeaway.
语言要点。
Language Takeaway.
So oftentimes in the wintertime when the air is very, very dry and maybe you have a cold,
所以通常在冬天，空气非常干燥，或者你可能感冒了，
you get this.
你会遇到这种情况。
This is the first thing we're talking about.
这是我们首先要讨论的。
That's right.
没错。
We have a sore throat.
我们喉咙痛。
Okay, so Chloe in the dialogue says, I woke up this morning and I had a really sore throat.
好的，所以对话中的Chloe说，我今天早上醒来时喉咙很痛。
Right.
对。
So let's take a look at those two words.
让我们看看这两个词。
We know throat is the part of your neck, right?
我们知道throat是你脖子的部分，对吧？
Right.
对。
Connects your head to your body.
连接你的头和身体。
That's right.
没错。
And the word sore.
而sore这个词。
Sore means it hurts.
Sore意思是疼痛。
So I could have a sore back or sore knees.
所以我可能背痛或膝盖痛。
Sore is basically an adjective that describes pain.
Sore基本上是一个描述疼痛的形容词。
Pain.
疼。
So you have an ache in your throat.
所以你的喉咙疼。
All right.
好的。
Chloe has a sore throat.
克洛伊喉咙痛。
And well, she said that she has this sore throat and the doctor says, I see.
嗯，她说她喉咙痛，医生就说，我明白了。
Yes, you do sound rather croaky.
是的，你听起来确实有点沙哑。
Okay.
好的。
Croaky is a way to describe the way a person sounds, especially when they're talking and
“沙哑”是用来形容一个人说话时的声音，尤其是当他们说话时，
maybe their voice I think is very deep or rough.
可能声音很低或很粗。
Right.
对。
So usually if you have a sore throat or a very bad cough, you sound a little bit croaky.
所以通常如果你喉咙痛或咳嗽得很厉害，你的声音会有点沙哑。
So you're like, hey, my throat hurts a little bit.
就像你这样说：“嘿，我喉咙有点疼。”
Exactly.
没错。
Not a very nice way to sound.
这种声音可不好听。
It comes from the way that frogs croak, right?
它来自青蛙呱呱叫的方式，对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
That's the sound that frogs make.
那就是青蛙发出的声音。
They croak.
它们呱呱叫。
So yeah, sometimes when you do have a sore throat or a very bad cough, people say that
所以，是的，有时候当你喉咙痛或咳嗽得很厉害时，人们会说
you have a frog in your throat.
你喉咙里有只青蛙。
Right.
对。
All right.
好的。
So that's the word croaky.
所以这就是“沙哑”这个词。
Now moving on, if you have a sore throat, it's usually because your tonsils are swollen.
现在继续，如果你喉咙痛，通常是因为你的扁桃体肿了。
Okay.
好的。
So the first word here, tonsils, these are a body part.
这里的第一个词，“扁桃体”，是一个身体部位。
They're in your throat, the very back of your throat, and you usually have two of them.
它们在你的喉咙里，喉咙的最深处，通常你有两个。
Some people don't have any though.
不过有些人一个都没有。
Right.
对。
Some people get them removed.
有些人把它们切除了。
They're like little balls in the back of your throat.
它们就像喉咙后面的小圆球。
And I don't really know what they do.
我真的不知道它们有什么用。
I think they pick up some, I don't know what they do.
我觉得它们能捕捉一些……我不知道它们有什么用。
I don't think you need them actually, because a lot of people have them taken out when they're
我觉得你其实不需要它们，因为很多人小时候就把它们切除了。
young.
小时候。
But tonsils when they are infected or when they are swollen are very, very painful.
但是扁桃体感染或肿胀时，会非常非常疼。
You can have really bad sore throats.
你可能会喉咙痛得很厉害。
Right.
对。
And it can cause fevers and stuff like that.
而且还会引起发烧之类的症状。
So some people get them removed.
所以有些人会把它们切掉。
And well, as we said, your tonsils are swollen.
嗯，就像我们说的，你的扁桃体肿了。
So if they are swollen, that means they are big.
所以如果它们肿了，就意味着它们变大了。
That's right.
没错。
So swollen means they're bigger than normal.
所以“肿了”意味着它们比正常情况大。
And you can say this about many different things.
你可以用这个词来形容很多不同的东西。
For example, maybe someone stepped on my toe and my toe really hurts and I looked down
比如，可能有人踩了我的脚趾，我的脚趾很疼，我低头一看，
and it's swollen.
它肿了。
That means my toe got bigger.
这意味着我的脚趾变大了。
Okay.
好的。
So this is an adjective when something is swollen.
所以这是一个形容词，用来描述某物肿了。
But the verb form to say that something swells.
但动词形式是“swell”，表示某物肿胀。
It gets bigger.
它变大。
It gets bigger to swell.
变大就是“swell”。
Or the adjective, it is swollen.
或者形容词形式是“swollen”。
All right.
好的。
And now she was talking a little bit about her sinuses.
现在她稍微谈到了她的鼻窦。
Her sinuses are a little blocked up.
她的鼻窦有点堵塞。
So sinuses are in your face.
所以鼻窦在你的脸上。
You have them in your nose and under your eyes.
它们在你的鼻子里和眼睛下面。
And when they hurt, it's actually quite painful.
当它们疼的时候，其实挺难受的。
And people say that sometimes their sinuses are aggravated or they have bad sinuses.
人们有时会说他们的鼻窦发炎了，或者鼻窦不好。
This means they're having a hard time breathing or their face is sore, their eyes are sore.
这意味着他们呼吸困难，或者脸疼、眼睛疼。
It's very common.
这很常见。
Okay.
好的。
So that's sinuses.
所以这就是鼻窦。
Isn't there actually a condition that if you have blocked sinuses all the time, they call
是不是有一种情况，如果你一直鼻窦堵塞，他们叫
it sinusitis.
它鼻窦炎？
Sinusitis.
鼻窦炎。
Yeah.
是的。
So that's a problem that comes back again and again.
所以这是一个反复出现的问题。
Okay.
好的。
And the doctor also recommended her to rest because she is highly contagious.
医生还建议她休息，因为她有很强的传染性。
Okay.
好的。
So you want to stay away from people who are contagious.
所以你要远离有传染性的人。
This means that what disease they have or what illness they have can affect other people.
这意味着他们得的病或疾病会传染给别人。
So if I have the flu, Marco, and I come to work, it's pretty contagious.
所以如果我有流感，马可，我来上班，这很有传染性。
It's very likely that you will get the flu.
你很可能也会得流感。
That's right.
没错。
So a flu is very highly contagious or many other things are highly contagious.
所以流感传染性很强，或者很多其他东西传染性也很强。
For example, pink eye is very contagious.
比如，红眼病传染性很强。
But you know, cancer is not contagious.
但你知道，癌症不会传染。
If you have cancer, I can't get it from touching you.
如果你得了癌症，我不会因为碰了你而感染。
Right.
对。
Very good.
很好。
So contagious.
所以是传染性的。
All right.
好了。
Why don't we go back and listen to our dialogue again and we'll be back in a little bit to
我们不如回去再听一遍对话，一会儿再回来
talk about Fluency Builder.
讨论“流利度构建”部分。
Good afternoon, Chloe.
下午好，克洛伊。
I'm Dr. Evans.
我是埃文斯医生。
What seems to be the problem?
有什么问题吗？
Hi, Dr. Evans.
你好，埃文斯医生。
Thanks for seeing me on such short notice.
谢谢你这么快就接诊我。
When I woke up this morning, I had a really sore throat and a really bad cough.
今天早上醒来时，我喉咙很痛，咳嗽得很厉害。
I think I'm coming down with the flu.
我想我可能得了流感。
I see.
我明白了。
Yes, you do sound rather croaky.
是的，你听起来确实声音沙哑。
Well, let's have a look, shall we?
好吧，让我们检查一下，好吗？
Could you please open your mouth and say, ah?
请张开嘴，说“啊”，好吗？
Ah.
啊。
Good.
好的。
Yes.
是的。
Your tonsils are a little swollen and red.
你的扁桃体有点红肿。
How are your ears?
你的耳朵怎么样？
Blocked at all?
有没有堵塞？
A little, actually.
实际上有点。
My sinuses are a little blocked up as well.
我的鼻窦也有点堵塞。
I really feel terrible.
我真的感觉很难受。
OK, Chloe.
好的，克洛伊。
Can you please breathe in and out slowly for me while I listen to your chest?
请慢慢地吸气和呼气，我来听一下你的胸部。
Wow, you really are all bunged up.
哇，你确实堵得很厉害。
You don't sound too good at all.
你听起来状态很不好。
OK, I'm going to set you up with a bunch of antibiotics.
好的，我会给你开一些抗生素。
You will need to take these orange pills twice a day and these blue pills every evening.
这些橙色药片每天吃两次，这些蓝色药片每天晚上吃。
You will also have to take this cough medicine three times a day after meals.
你还需要每天饭后三次服用这种止咳药。
Finally, I am giving you an inhaler to use every time you feel breathless, just to clear
最后，我给你一个吸入器，每次感觉气短时使用，用来清理
up your lungs.
你的肺部。
Whoa, so many drugs.
哇，这么多药。
Ah, I hate swallowing pills.
啊，我讨厌吞药片。
Am I able to go to work?
我能去上班吗？
Absolutely not.
绝对不行。
You are highly contagious.
你具有很强的传染性。
You don't want to infect the rest of your co-workers, do you?
你不想传染给其他同事，对吧？
I recommend staying in bed for at least three days and drinking plenty of fluids so you
我建议你至少卧床休息三天，多喝水，这样
don't get weak and dehydrated.
就不会虚弱和脱水。
You can catch up on all the latest TV shows and movies.
你可以补看最新的电视剧和电影。
OK.
好的。
Would you mind writing me a doctor's note for work?
你能给我开一张病假条吗？
Otherwise, they may think I'm faking it.
否则，他们可能以为我在装病。
Sure, no problem.
当然，没问题。
Here you are.
给你。
Now, off home and away to bed.
现在，回家上床休息吧。
If you have any questions, just give me a call.
如果你有任何问题，给我打电话。
Feel better soon and take care.
祝你早日康复，保重。
Thanks doc.
谢谢医生。
Bye.
再见。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now let's take a look at four key phrases that we have prepared for you on Fluency Builder.
现在让我们看看我们为“流利度构建”准备的四个关键短语。
So, Chloe goes in to see her doctor, Dr. Evans, and she says, thanks for seeing me on such
所以，克洛伊去看她的医生埃文斯医生，她说，谢谢你这么快就接诊我。
short notice.
这么快是什么意思？
What's short notice?
什么是“短时间通知”？
All right.
好的。
So basically, Chloe made an appointment with the doctor very late or very suddenly.
基本上，克洛伊很晚或很突然地预约了医生。
So that's a short notice.
所以那就是“短时间通知”。
Great.
很好。
So, for example, it's Friday night and she needs to make an appointment for Saturday
例如，现在是周五晚上，她需要预约周六
morning.
早上。
That's pretty short notice.
那时间就很短。
That's not calling the doctor in advance.
那不是提前预约医生。
You can say this also when you're talking to friends.
你和朋友说话时也可以这么说。
You know, I'm really sorry to cancel on such short notice, but I can't go to dinner tonight.
你知道，我很抱歉这么临时取消，但我今晚不能去吃饭了。
Right.
对。
So I think it's very interesting, the whole structure as you see on such short notice.
所以我觉得整个结构“on such short notice”很有趣。
So as you said, your example, I'm really sorry to cancel on such short notice.
就像你说的，你的例子：我很抱歉这么临时取消。
On short notice.
临时通知。
On such short notice.
这么临时通知。
That's right.
没错。
All right.
好的。
So moving on to our second phrase, Chloe was explaining that she doesn't feel very well
那么转到我们的第二个短语，克洛伊在解释她感觉不太舒服。
and she said, I think I'm coming down with the flu.
她说：“我觉得我好像要得流感了。”
Okay.
好的。
So let's look at this verbal phrase here, coming down with.
那我们来看看这个动词短语“coming down with”。
Okay.
好的。
So you can come down with many different illnesses, but the verb here means, this is the beginning
你可以“coming down with”很多不同的疾病，但这里的动词意思是，这是
of my illness.
我生病的开始。
So I'm starting to feel the effects.
所以我开始感觉到症状了。
Like you said, Marco, I'm feeling some symptoms.
就像你说的，Marco，我感觉有些症状。
So I'm starting to get sick, right?
所以我开始生病了，对吧？
I'm coming down with a fever.
我快要发烧了。
Or I think I'm coming down with a cold.
或者我觉得我快要感冒了。
Very common.
很常见。
All right.
好的。
And the doctor started to check Chloe, how she was breathing.
然后医生开始检查Chloe的呼吸情况。
And I think he listened to her lungs with his, what is it called?
我想他用他的——那个叫什么来着——听了她的肺部？
A stethoscope.
听诊器。
Stethoscope.
And he said, wow, you are really all bunged up.
然后他说：“哇，你真是堵得厉害。”
All right.
好的。
So here he's basically saying that she's very congested.
这里他基本上是说她非常鼻塞/充血。
That means that her breathing passageways, like in her nose and her throat and her chest,
这意味着她的呼吸通道，比如鼻子、喉咙和胸部，
are very stuffy.
都很不通畅。
There's things in them.
里面有东西。
Usually mucus.
通常是黏液。
Yeah, phlegm.
对，痰。
Phlegm.
痰。
These are things that, you know what's in your nose when you have a cold and you have
这些东西就是——你知道感冒时鼻子里有什么，你得
to blow it out?
擤出来吗？
That's phlegm and mucus.
那就是痰和黏液。
Yeah.
嗯。
Not a very pretty thing.
不是什么好看的东西。
No.
不是。
Very disgusting, actually.
实际上很恶心。
So maybe we should move on to our next item.
所以我们也许该进入下一个话题了。
All right.
好的。
So she's all bunged up.
所以她堵得很厉害。
And clear up.
还有“clear up”。
And so he recommended a couple of different medicine, such as antibiotics, some pills,
所以他推荐了几种不同的药，比如抗生素、一些药片，
and he also gave her an inhaler to clear up her lungs.
还给了她一个吸入器来清理肺部。
Okay.
好的。
So an inhaler is basically a device that you use to put steroids in your lungs that will
吸入器基本上是一种装置，用来把类固醇送入肺部，
help you breathe.
帮助你呼吸。
So some people, when they're running or they're walking, they're very short of breath and
有些人跑步或走路时，会喘不上气，
they can't breathe.
无法呼吸。
Well, there's a problem with this, like asthma, and they need to breathe this little inhaler.
嗯，这可能是哮喘之类的问题，他们需要吸这个小吸入器。
It's like a little tube.
它像一个小管子。
I think you inhale medicine from this little tube.
我想你是从这个小管子里吸入药物。
Yeah.
嗯。
So the medicine helps open up your passageways.
所以药物有助于打开你的通道。
It helps you breathe and it's very important for some people.
它帮助你呼吸，对一些人来说非常重要。
But in the case of an illness, like your lungs are very congested, this helps you breathe
但在生病的情况下，比如你的肺部非常堵塞，这能帮你
on the short term.
短期呼吸。
Right.
对。
So to clear up is to allow air or the movement of something within your body, usually, I
所以“clear up”是让空气或体内的某种东西流动起来，通常，
think.
我想是这样。
Right.
对。
But to clear up isn't necessarily about air.
但“clear up”不一定只跟空气有关。
It's basically a way to say that it will make this problem go away.
它基本上是说让这个问题消失。
To clear something up is to make the problem go.
“Clear something up”就是让问题消失。
Right.
对。
So I guess if you get medicine from a doctor, he'll say, okay, this will help you clear
所以我想如果你从医生那里拿到药，他会说：“好的，这能帮你
up your throat.
清理喉咙。”
Right.
对。
Or if you have a problem with acne, maybe your doctor will give you some cream to help
或者如果你有痘痘问题，医生可能会给你一些药膏来
clear up your acne, make it go away.
清理痘痘，让它消失。
Clear up your skin.
清理你的皮肤。
Okay.
好的。
So a lot of great examples there.
所以有很多很好的例子。
Why don't we go back and listen to the dialogue one last time.
我们不如回去再听一遍对话吧。
Good afternoon, Chloe.
下午好，Chloe。
I'm Dr. Evans.
我是Evans医生。
What seems to be the problem?
有什么问题吗？
Hi, Dr. Evans.
你好，Evans医生。
Thanks for seeing me on such short notice.
谢谢你这么快就给我看病。
When I woke up this morning, I had a really sore throat and a really bad cough.
今天早上醒来时，我喉咙很痛，咳嗽得很厉害。
I think I'm coming down with the flu.
我觉得我好像要得流感了。
I see.
我明白了。
Yes, you do sound rather croaky.
是的，你听起来确实声音沙哑。
Well, let's have a look, shall we?
好吧，让我们检查一下，好吗？
Could you please open your mouth and say, ah?
能请你张开嘴说“啊”吗？
Ah.
啊。
Good.
好的。
Yes.
是的。
Your tonsils are a little swollen and red.
你的扁桃体有点红肿。
How are your ears?
你的耳朵怎么样？
Blocked at all?
有没有堵塞的感觉？
A little, actually.
其实有一点。
My sinuses are a little blocked up as well.
我的鼻窦也有点堵塞。
I really feel terrible.
我真的感觉很难受。
Okay, Chloe.
好的，克洛伊。
Can you please breathe in and out slowly for me while I listen to your chest?
请你在我听你胸口的时候慢慢吸气和呼气好吗？
Wow, you really are all bunged up.
哇，你真是堵得厉害。
You don't sound too good at all.
你听起来状态很不好。
Okay, I'm going to set you up with a bunch of antibiotics.
好的，我会给你开一堆抗生素。
You will need to take these orange pills twice a day and these blue pills every evening.
你需要每天吃两次这些橙色药丸，每天晚上吃这些蓝色药丸。
You will also have to take this cough medicine three times a day after meals.
你还需要每天饭后三次服用这种止咳药。
Finally, I am giving you an inhaler to use every time you feel breathless, just to clear
最后，我给你一个吸入器，每次感觉喘不过气时使用，用来清理
up your lungs.
你的肺部。
Whoa, so many drugs.
哇，这么多药。
Ah, I hate swallowing pills.
啊，我讨厌吞药片。
Am I able to go to work?
我能去上班吗？
Absolutely not.
绝对不行。
You are highly contagious.
你具有很强的传染性。
You don't want to infect the rest of your co-workers, do you?
你不想传染给其他同事，对吧？
I recommend staying in bed for at least three days and drinking plenty of fluids so you
我建议你至少卧床休息三天，多喝水，这样你
don't get weak and dehydrated.
就不会虚弱和脱水。
You can catch up on all the latest TV shows and movies.
你可以补看所有最新的电视剧和电影。
Okay.
好吧。
Would you mind writing me a doctor's note for work?
你能帮我开一张病假条给公司吗？
Otherwise, they may think I'm faking it.
否则，他们可能会以为我在装病。
Sure, no problem.
当然，没问题。
Here you are.
给你。
Now, off home and away to bed.
现在，回家上床休息吧。
If you have any questions, just give me a call.
如果你有任何问题，随时给我打电话。
Feel better soon and take care.
祝你早日康复，保重。
Thanks doc.
谢谢医生。
Bye.
再见。
All right, so talking about illnesses and being contagious, we mentioned this pink eye
好的，那么说到生病和传染性，我们提到了红眼病。
illness before.
以前得过病。
So this is the colloquial way of saying conjunctivitis, which is, I don't know if anyone has ever
所以这是结膜炎的口语说法，我不知道有没有人得过。
gotten it, your eye gets very, very red for a prolonged period of time.
得了之后，眼睛会长时间变得非常非常红。
That's right.
没错。
And it itches a lot.
而且会很痒。
It itches.
很痒。
And so already your eye is very red or very pink, like the name says, but you really want
所以就像名字说的那样，你的眼睛已经很红或很粉了，但你真的很想。
to scratch it and itch it and it's really hard not to.
去抓它、挠它，而且很难忍住不这么做。
Yeah.
是啊。
And I think you treat it by means of some eye drops.
我觉得治疗方法是滴一些眼药水。
Yeah.
嗯。
And you have to wait.
而且你得等着。
I actually had a very bad case of pink eye once that I couldn't just clear up with drops.
我其实得过一次很严重的红眼病，光靠眼药水好不了。
The doctor gave me some eye drops.
医生给了我一些眼药水。
They were so strong that I put them in my eye and I can taste them.
药效太强了，我滴进眼睛后居然能尝到味道。
Oh, wow.
哦，哇。
Yeah.
是啊。
So apparently, yeah, it's very strange and it wouldn't clear up.
所以很明显，这很奇怪，而且一直没好。
So then I had to get some kind of like a clear gel put in my eye and my eye patched up for
然后我不得不在眼睛里放一种透明的凝胶，眼睛被包扎起来。
like two days.
大概两天。
Oh wow.
哦，哇。
Yeah.
是啊。
So I was running around with one eye.
所以我当时就一只眼睛到处跑。
It was crazy.
那真是疯了。
I've never had it, but I know that it's very, very contagious, like we were saying earlier.
我从来没得过，但我知道它传染性很强，就像我们之前说的。
And so if a student at a school gets pink eye, all the parents get very nervous because
所以如果学校里有学生得了红眼病，所有家长都会很紧张，因为
it's very, very likely that he or she will give it to another person.
他或她很可能会传染给别人。
Yeah.
是啊。
Because, you know, kids, if you touch your eye and you touch someone else, all of a sudden
因为，你知道，孩子们，如果你摸了自己的眼睛又去摸别人，突然之间
they have this disease.
他们就会得这个病。
Exactly.
没错。
So, yeah, it's very common thing.
所以，是啊，这是很常见的事。
And I think with especially with kids, they always get all these things, pink eye, measles.
而且我觉得尤其是孩子们，他们总是会得这些病，红眼病、麻疹。
They get chickenpox.
他们会得水痘。
Chickenpox.
水痘。
A lot of different diseases.
很多不同的病。
We actually have a lesson on chickenpox.
我们其实有一节关于水痘的课。
You guys should check that one out.
你们应该去看看那一节。
But if you have any questions, any comments or any other doubts, please come to EnglishPod.com
但如果你们有任何问题、任何评论或任何其他疑问，请来EnglishPod.com
where we're there to answer them.
我们在那里回答这些问题。
We'll see you there.
我们到时候见。
Bye.
再见。
Thanks for watching EnglishPod.
感谢收看EnglishPod。